<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Ivan</title><link>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Ivan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The One That Never Loses Their Way</title><link>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/the_one_that_never_loses_their_way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/the_one_that_never_loses_their_way/</guid><description>Eigenvalues and eigenvectors are often cited as crucial components in data science and machine learning, yet it is perplexing why they are not emphasized more in traditional data science curricula. Seeking answers, I pursued a second major in Mathematics and Statistics in my university.
The study dates back to 1858, when mathematician Arthur Cayley made a groundbreaking discovery with the Cayley-Hamilton theorem. This theorem states that if λ (the eigenvalue) is substituted with the original matrix, the characteristic polynomial for a matrix will remain true.</description></item><item><title>Why Happily Ever Afters Doesn't Exist</title><link>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/why_happily_ever_afters_doesnt_exist/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/why_happily_ever_afters_doesnt_exist/</guid><description>In 1978, researchers at Northwestern University and the University of Massachusetts asked recent Illinois State Lottery winners whose prizes ranged from $50,000 to $1 million, as well as recent victims of catastrophic accidents who were now paraplegic or quadriplegic, about their happiness. The two groups were asked to rate their level of enjoyment from everyday activities such as talking to friends, watching TV, eating breakfast, laughing at a joke, or receiving a compliment.</description></item><item><title>First Snorkeling Day Trip</title><link>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/first_snorkeling_day_trip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/first_snorkeling_day_trip/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to try diving or snorkeling in the ocean. I like pretty things and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen pictures of the beautiful underwater world. But I also had quite a bit of fear towards the deep sea. So recently, I decided to join StudyPerth for a snorkeling day trip to face my fears and experience something new.
Early in the morning, we gathered at StudyPerth Student Hub for an attendance check.</description></item><item><title>How I Learnt to Embrace Emptiness</title><link>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/how_i_learnt_to_embrace_emptiness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://orange-my-cat.github.io/blog/how_i_learnt_to_embrace_emptiness/</guid><description>Have you ever found yourself wondering why you&amp;rsquo;re writing something? Or questioning your ability to write at all? Do you feel like you have nothing to write about, or that you&amp;rsquo;re not sure why you even want to write in the first place? These thoughts, combined with a feeling of emptiness, are something I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced more than a few times in my life.
Emptiness can be characterized by emotional numbness, a lack of purpose and meaning, feeling disconnected, and acting mechanically or without enthusiasm.</description></item></channel></rss>